These are four of my favorite low-tech
devices.
Previously, you guys liked the video
that I did [music] about my top five
buy-for-life items, and also my top
favorite niche tech items that have
improved my life. So, I thought in this
video I would share one of my favorite
categories of
>> [music]
>> niche technology, which are ink devices.
If you're not familiar with ink devices,
this is what a regular display looks
like,
>> [music]
>> and this is an ink display. So, what
makes ink devices so special is that
compared to regular screens, they
literally emit no light. So, it [music]
looks like actual paper when you're just
looking at it. And this makes it really
nice to read things, to take notes on
it, or for displaying information. Like,
there's no eye strain, there's no blue
light that could disrupt your circadian
rhythm, and there aren't super [music]
fast refresh rates. So, ink devices,
they kind of remove a lot of the
negative aspects of traditional screens.
So, ink screens have actually been
around for a long time now, but it's
only recently in the past few years that
there's been a lot more companies
actually innovating and improving this
technology, and there's also a trend
towards using these screens for things
like reading books and taking notes
because it's a lot nicer than using a
regular screen. [music]
And I also just see it more in my daily
life now. Like, I see it in the bus
stop, they use an ink screen, and even
the supermarket. [music]
Personally, I think ink screens are one
of the most underrated niche technology
[music] that you can use to help you
improve your life. It helps you
integrate technology in a better way
into your own life without having a
bunch of screens and [music] bunch of
notifications all the time. So, in this
video I'll share with you four of my
favorite ink devices that I have been
using in my life, and hopefully that
inspires you to maybe look into this
technology more. Starting with the first
one. So, the first one is my e-reader,
the Boox Palma. So, I've been using this
for 3 years now, and it's my favorite
way to read books.
I used to have a Kindle when I was in
high school, and I had that for about 10
years, but 3 years ago I upgraded to
this one, and I much prefer this one
over a Kindle for a few reasons. First
of all, Kindle recently has made a few
updates that makes it harder for you to
own your own books like they made it so
that older versions of Kindles were no
longer supported and you were forced to
buy a new one.
>> [music]
>> And also they made it really difficult
to upload or download books that you
have purchased. [music] So one of the
reasons I like the Book Nook is because
it runs Android and so it means that you
can
>> [music]
>> really customize it however you want and
install any apps that you want. And so
there's not really ever going to be a
situation [music] where this thing is
just going to stop working because the
company behind it doesn't want you to
use it anymore. Probably the bigger
reason and the initial reason why I
switched to this one is because of the
form factor. So a Kindle is kind of
bulky and like a traditional e-reader is
kind of bulky it's like kind of like the
size of a book. And this one is a phone
form factor so it's really nice to hold
and
because I put like a MagSafe thing on
the back of it, if I'm in bed, I can
easily just like lie down and read with
this.
And it really helps me read more often
because it's just easier to use and it's
a form factor that [music] I'm used to.
You might say that you can just read
books on your phone and I would agree
with you but [music]
if you compare the experience of reading
a book on your phone compared to reading
a book on this, it's just way nicer to
read on this and I can actually read
books for several hours on this so like
especially if I'm on a train or an
airplane versus my phone. Like on my
phone if I read for more than 30 minutes
I kind of get eye strain and especially
in public transportation it's really
hard to read on my phone without it like
really creating pretty significant eye
strain. In the past I've also used this
device as a dopamine detox device. When
I don't want to bring my phone out, I
can just bring this and still have
access to messaging apps, AI apps or
maps.
And depending on the version you get,
you can also get a SIM card
>> [music]
>> to get data on this. Of course I still
really like reading physical books but a
lot of times with physical books it's
extremely [music] bulky and really hard
to read and it's also hard to read
multiple books at a time which is what I
do a lot on this device. And if you
travel or you move around a lot, it's
not that realistic to have a collection
of physical books. If you study any
languages, this is also nice because you
can just, you know, tap to look up any
words or install different apps to read
different types of content. Like you can
even read manga on this device. For the
most part, I only use this at home and
when I'm traveling. I did make a video
on my setup with the Boox Palma a while
back if you want to check that out. So,
the second device that I want to share
is called the [music]
terminal. This is basically a picture
frame that is an e-ink device that you
can set up to display anything that you
want and it will just refresh
periodically throughout the day. So, for
me, I put this on a desk. I've had this
for over a year [music] now.
And I just have it show my calendar for
the whole week. So, this is makes it so
that at a glance I can see anything that
I have coming up without always having
to have the calendar app open or having
something [music] that has a lot of
features or a lot of notifications. This
is just kind of a passive thing that I
set up once and just continue to work.
I want to say [music] that the battery
lasts a few months. I rarely charge it.
And when I do charge it, it lasts for a
really long time. This one has a stand
or you can uh put on the wall. So, right
now I have it on the wall. And [music]
one underrated thing you can do with
this as well is you can set this up with
your calendar and then give it to
[music]
your family or your partner and so they
can see what your schedule looks like.
They recently came out with a bigger one
and I also [music] decided to get that
to display my YouTube stats so that I
can see at a glance without refreshing
YouTube Studio. [music] This one
actually has a magnet so, in theory, you
can put it on your fridge, but I think
my fridge the magnets aren't strong
enough because it keeps falling off.
But, the third device that I want
[music] to share is also a device made
by Boox and it's called the Boox Go,
which is [music] a tablet. So, this is
tablet that you can use for reading
documents, taking notes, or using as a
scratchpad. [music]
So, in terms of the OS, it's pretty much
the same as the Boox Palma. It runs
Android so you can customize it however
you want. Um I actually have it
connected [music] to my server using
Syncthing, so my books
my two books devices and my server syncs
all the books [music] together, so
they're all synced. So, what I mostly
use this for is reading things that are
in [music] an A4 size. So, for example,
textbooks,
documents, and sheet music. [music] So,
like guitar and piano, I use this cuz
you can mark it up as well.
And it's also really nice to use as a
scratchpad because the pen that it comes
with is [music] really responsive and
it's nice to draw on. So, one of the
cool things you can do with this as well
is that you can put in your own PDF, for
example, like a calendar or [music] kind
of like a planner, and then you can draw
on it and refresh it every single day.
The build quality [music] on this is
also really nice. It's really thin. The
pen has a magnetic holder right next to
it,
>> [music]
>> and there's even a backlight. If you
wanted to keep a digital journal where
you still write by hand, I think this is
also a really good solution. [music] For
me, I still prefer to journal with paper
and pen, and I still use like a a
regular [music] notebook. But, if you
were looking for something like that
where you can back it up and not be
scared of losing your actual journals, I
think this is a really good solution.
The main competitor that you probably
heard of
to this product is the reMarkable
tablet, [music]
and I did consider getting that one, but
I ended up getting this one because that
one had a bunch of upsells and monthly
subscriptions, and it was less
customizable compared to this one.
>> [music]
>> And it didn't seem like there were any
features that that one had that this one
didn't. And in many ways it seemed like
this one was better. But, if you use the
reMarkable, I'm curious to hear about
your experience, and let me know in the
comments below. So, the fourth device I
want to share is this one that I got
relatively recently. I got this earlier
this year, and this is called the XT E
Ink device. This is also a really thin
device. I think E Ink devices tend to be
on the thinner side, but this is a
really small e-reader. But, the beauty
of this device is that it's small enough
to be able to stick on the back of your
phone and it even has a magnet in it.
So, you can kind of carry it around like
that. [music] Compared to my main
e-reader, the Boox Palma, I don't really
bring this if I'm just going out on a
normal day because it's kind of
unrealistic to bring like both my phone
and an e-reader. It's it becomes way too
bulky in my [music] pockets. And so,
this kind of fills that gap where you
can easily carry this out. It can easily
fit in any of your pockets [music] and
it even sticks to the back of your phone
because it has a MagSafe
uh magnet on the back. Unlike the Boox
Palma, there are no apps, so it's far
[music] less customizable and it's
really just a folder that you can drag
and drop books onto
>> [music]
>> to read books on this. So, you can't
really install the Kindle app if that's
how you get books or a manga app if you
read manga. So, I would only recommend
this device for somebody that's really
comfortable getting their own ebooks, uh
really comfortable with getting ebooks
onto this device. Whereas the Boox Palma
is a much easier
device to set up and read [music] books
immediately. I did install a custom OS
on the XT-E Ink [music] and it just
makes it slightly more customizable with
the lock screen. I can make it show the
cover or just the page that [music] I'm
reading.
And besides that, there's pretty much no
difference. Using this kind of makes me
nostalgic for my iPhone Mini because it
kind of has that similar form factor and
it reminds me that this is the ideal
form factor of a phone. So, I'm looking
forward to foldable phones where I think
it's going to get smaller [music] again.
But yeah, this is a pretty neat little
device. I've also seen some people
combine their wallet and this device
into kind of like a bifold wallet, so
that also seems pretty interesting. But
yeah, that's pretty much it for my
favorite e-ink devices. Let me know what
you thought of this video. Let me know
what you thought of e-ink devices if you
use them and whether or not you like to
try them.
But, also let me know what type of
videos you would want me to make next.
Like, do you want me to make more tech
compilations or
>> [music]
>> do you want me to make other stuff?
Like, other stuff I make on the channel.
Let me know what other videos on my
channel that you've liked that you would
like me to make more of.
>> [music]
>> But yeah.
I'm going to try to respond to all the
comments and I'll see you there. And
I'll see you in the next video. Let's
get it. [music]